When people ask you to do things they want to hang out with you by the way hang out just means to do
当人们要求你做他们想和你一起出去玩的事情时，出去玩只是意味着做
something together.
在一起的东西。
Often in a very casual way or go over to someone's house and just be there maybe play video games together
通常以一种非常随意的方式，或者去某人家，只是在那里，也许一起玩电子游戏
or whatever talk if people ask you to do things and you can't or you don't want to.
或任何谈话，如果人们要求你做某事而你不能或你不想做。
And you need to say no.
你需要说不。
You have to know how to do that politely because if you just say no it's rude it's rude.
你必须知道如何礼貌地做到这一点，因为如果你只是说不，那就是粗鲁了。
You can't just say no.
你不能只是说不。
You have to say it in a certain way so we're gonna go over a couple of expressions.
你必须以某种方式说出来，所以我们要复习几个表达方式。
We can use to say no baseline OK.
我们可以说没有基线 OK。
If I offer you a piece of candy and you want to say no to that fine.
如果我给你一块糖果，而你想拒绝那个罚款。
Hey you want a piece of candy care for a piece of candy.
嘿，你想要一块糖果照顾一块糖果。
No no thanks.
不，不，谢谢。
No thanks or no they're fine.
不，谢谢或不，他们很好。
You can also say I'm good I'm good.
你也可以说我很好我很好。
Means no.
表示没有。
Do you need anything.
你需要什么吗。
I'm going out to the supermarket.
我要去超市。
I'm good I'm good very polite but when it comes to refusing an invitation that's kind of a bigger thing
我很好，我很好，很有礼貌，但是当涉及到拒绝邀请时，这是一件更大的事情
right.
正确的。
So we can't just say no thanks and we can't just say no.
所以我们不能只说不，谢谢，也不能只说不。
We should say a little bit more.
我们应该多说一点。
And it depends on the situation.
这取决于情况。
So let's go through these phrases.
那么让我们来看看这些短语。
I'd love to but.
我很乐意但是。
So if you're being honest this is a good one.
所以，如果你是诚实的，这是一个很好的。
Maybe you really want to and maybe you really can't.
也许你真的想要，也许你真的不能。
You're so busy this week is just crazy hectic it's hectic hectic means really busy.
你这周太忙了，简直是疯狂的忙碌，忙碌的忙碌意味着真的很忙。
I'd love to but this week is just totally hectic my whole week is booked.
我很想去，但这周太忙了，我的整个星期都订满了。
I don't think I can go.
我不认为我可以去。
I'd love to but I can't.
我很想，但我做不到。
All right.
好的。
I just can't I'm too busy.
我不能，我太忙了。
Then you can say next time I wish I could.
然后你可以说下次我希望我能。
I wish I could but I really wish I could but I have to be in the office until 10:00 p.m. tonight.
我希望我能，但我真的希望我能，但我必须在办公室直到晚上 10:00。今晚。
So I really can't.
所以我真的不能。
I wish I could but I can't.
我希望我能，但我不能。
I wish I could.
我希望我能。
I wish I could have dinner tonight but I'm actually leaving to drive to my hometown and it's a seven
我希望今晚能吃晚饭，但实际上我要开车回家乡了，现在是七点
hour drive so I have to leave earlier.
一个小时的车程，所以我必须早点离开。
I wish I could.
我希望我能。
I wish I could but I need to.
我希望我能，但我需要。
I need to leave at 3 p.m. Now of course in many situations people will tell a little tiny little what
我需要在下午 3 点离开。现在当然在许多情况下人们会告诉一点点什么
we would call white lie and this is where we really don't have something to do or maybe we're just going
我们会称之为善意的谎言，这是我们真的无事可做的地方，或者我们只是要去
to go home and hang out.
回家闲逛。
We just don't want to go.
我们只是不想去。
Right.
正确的。
So we could say I'd love to but I really can't then.
所以我们可以说我很愿意，但那时我真的不能。
And this happens and if you want to do this you can.
这发生了，如果你想这样做，你可以。
You could say I've got other plans.
你可以说我有其他计划。
I I'd love to but I can't.
我很想，但我做不到。
I've got plans or I've got other plans I've got other things going on now.
我有计划或者我有其他计划 我现在有其他事情要做。
Those plans could be sitting at home and watching a movie sitting at home just watching Netflix or whatever.
这些计划可能是坐在家里看电影，坐在家里看 Netflix 或其他什么。
So you do have plans but they're not plans with other people.
所以你确实有计划，但他们不是与其他人的计划。
That's OK.
没关系。
Right.
正确的。
Saying I've got plans.
说我有计划。
It's better than saying no no.
总比说不不好。
If you just don't feel like it you can say that directly.
如果你只是不喜欢它，你可以直接说。
But we often make it softer by saying not really I'm not really up to it I'm not really up to it or
但我们经常说不是真的 我不是真的能做到 我不太能做到或
I'm not really in the mood if we say I'm not in the mood.
如果我们说我没有心情，我真的没有心情。
It sounds a little bit moody.
听起来有点喜怒无常。
It sounds a little bit kind of grumpy grumpy means a bit angry a bit grumpy so we say I'm not really
听起来有点脾气暴躁有点生气有点暴躁所以我们说我不是真的
in the mood.
有兴致。
It softens it saying not really is a way to make it sound a little less direct.
它软化了它，说不是真的是一种让它听起来不那么直接的方法。
Or we could say I don't really feel like it.
或者我们可以说我真的不喜欢它。
I don't really don't really feel really.
我真的不觉得真的。
I don't really feel like it.
我真的不喜欢。
I don't really feel like it unfortunately.
不幸的是，我真的不喜欢它。
Maybe it's a time thing maybe it's just because you really don't have time.
也许这是一个时间问题，也许只是因为你真的没有时间。
Hey I'm gonna go grab some dinner at about 7 o'clock.
嘿，我要在七点左右去吃晚饭。
Do you want to go along.
你要不要一起去。
Yeah.
是的。
Sounds great.
听起来很棒。
I'd love to.
我想要。
What time.
什么时候。
Seven to seven doesn't really work for me.
七点到七点真的不适合我。
I'm going to be in the office until 8:00.
我将在办公室工作到 8:00。
Could we push it back to 8:00.
我们能不能把它推回到8:00。
Or could we push it to 8:00.
或者我们可以把它推到 8:00。
Or how about 8:00.
或者8:00怎么样。
So when you want to check the time we often use.
所以当你要检查的时候我们经常使用。
Work for.
为。。。工作。
Yeah.
是的。
We use work for to ask whether a time is OK for another person.
我们用 work for 来询问一个时间是否适合另一个人。
Does seven work for you.
七对你有用吗？
Sounds weird right.
听起来很奇怪吧。
We say it to seven worked for you now seven doesn't really work for me.
我们说七对你有用，现在七对我不起作用。
How about 8:00.
8:00 怎么样。
Or could we push it to 8:00.
或者我们可以把它推到 8:00。
Could we move it to 9:00.
我们可以把它移到 9:00。
Or could we move it to tomorrow.
或者我们可以把它移到明天。
Also very very common.
也非常非常常见。
So those are the common ways that we refuse if somebody asks us to do something.
因此，如果有人要求我们做某事，这些是我们拒绝的常见方式。
It's actually harder to refuse than to agree.
其实拒绝比同意更难。
Because if you want to agree again you just say yeah.
因为如果您想再次同意，您只需说是。
Great.
伟大的。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Absolutely fantastic.
绝对精彩。
Yeah.
是的。
OK right.
好的没错。
That's easy.
这很容易。
Now I did mention before ways to agree.
现在我确实提到了同意的方式。
So we know those but I wanted to just review them and have them clearly written down so that they're
所以我们知道这些，但我只想回顾一下，并把它们清楚地写下来，这样它们就可以
easier to remember and also talk about how we can show a little bit less excitement if we need to.
更容易记住，如果需要的话，还可以谈论我们如何才能表现得不那么兴奋。
So as I mentioned before someone invites you to do something.
所以正如我之前提到的，有人邀请你做某事。
Want to go grab a cup of coffee.
想去喝杯咖啡。
Sounds great.
听起来很棒。
Me and some friends are going out later tonight.
我和一些朋友今晚晚些时候要出去。
Would you care to come along.
你愿意一起来吗？
Sure.
当然。
What time to get the time right.
什么时间才能把握好时机。
Absolutely.
绝对地。
I'm thinking about going to get a sandwich for lunch.
我正在考虑去买个三明治当午餐。
You want to go with me.
你想和我一起去。
Absolutely.
绝对地。
I'd love to.
我想要。
I'll be there.
我会在那里。
I'll be there is usually for more of a party.
我通常会在那里参加更多的聚会。
Hey I'm having a party this weekend on Friday and I'm wondering if you'd like to go.
嘿，我这个周末星期五要参加一个聚会，我想知道你是否愿意去。
I'm wondering if is by the way also very common.
我想知道顺便说一句是否也很常见。
I'm wondering if you'd you would you'd you'd like to to come you'd like to join us.
我想知道你是否愿意你想来你想加入我们。
I'm wondering if is a very common way as well to sound like it's it's great if you do but no pressure.
我想知道是否也是一种非常常见的方式，听起来如果你这样做很好，但没有压力。
Right.
正确的。
Wondering if you'd like to I'll be there.
想知道你是否愿意，我会在那里。
I'll be there.
我会在那里。
You can use to express that you're excited about going but only for party situations.
你可以用来表达你很高兴去，但仅限于聚会场合。
If if I want to eat dinner with you and it's just you and me and you say I'll be there.
如果我想和你一起吃晚饭，只有你和我，你说我会在那里。
Maybe that's a little bit weird because it's just you and I.
也许这有点奇怪，因为只有你和我。
Right.
正确的。
So usually I'll be there as for more of a social thing where there are more people a group of people
所以通常我会在那里，因为更多的人是一群人
together three or four people or 20 or 30 people.
三四个人或20或30人。
I'll be there.
我会在那里。
All right.
好的。
Is often a little bit less excited but it depends on how you say it.
通常不那么兴奋，但这取决于你怎么说。
If you say all right.
如果你说好吧。
All right.
好的。
So I'm very excited if you say all right if you're gonna do this you roll your eyes roll your eyes.
所以我很兴奋，如果你说好吧，如果你要做这个，你就翻白眼。
That means maybe you don't really want to go but you're agreeing anyway.
这意味着也许你真的不想去，但你还是同意了。
OK why not.
好啊，为什么不。
OK.
好的。
Why not.
为什么不。
This doesn't mean you're excited it just means you're agreeing OK.
这并不意味着你很兴奋，它只是意味着你同意了。
Is like that.
是这样的。
Yes it's positive but it's not excited.
是的，这是积极的，但并不兴奋。
And then why not means you can't think of another reason or another thing you have to do.
然后为什么不意味着你想不出另一个原因或你必须做的另一件事。
You can't think of a reason to say no.
你想不出拒绝的理由。
So this does not sound excited.
所以这听起来并不令人兴奋。
Sure.
当然。
I've got nothing else going on.
我没有其他事情发生。
It's a little weird but people do say it quite often.
这有点奇怪，但人们确实经常这么说。
It means I can't think of anything else I should do so yeah I guess I will.
这意味着我想不出我应该做的任何其他事情，是的，我想我会的。
And people will say I.
人们会说我。
I guess so I guess so really expresses that you're not excited.
我猜所以我猜所以真的表达了你不兴奋。
You wouldn't say I guess so.
你不会说我猜是的。
People say I guess so I will but I'm not super excited about it.
人们说我猜我会的，但我对此并不感到非常兴奋。
These are all extremely common ways to say yes at different levels of excitement or enthusiasm.
这些都是在不同程度的兴奋或热情时说“是”的非常常见的方式。